< Nicolas Mewhirter />

Email: mewhirter@wisc.edu | Phone: 608-642-1693 | Website: https://nicolasm42.github.io/

Personal Summary------

Ambitious, creative programmer with a desire to make my mark on the world of software development. From my time at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, as-well as through interning and working on personal projects, I've gained the experience and skills necessary to be successful in my ever-expanding field.

Work Experience-----

Software Developer Intern

Epic | Verona, WI | Full-time | June 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Worked as a developer on an internal software project
- Attended team meetings, collected feedback on my work from fellow developers and UX designers
- Presented my work to interested external parties, demoed to other full-time developers

Student Assistant (Level 3)

University of Wisconsin-Madison, College Library Computer Lab | Part-time | Sept. 2019 - May 2021

- Fulfilled patron inquiries and requests
- Troubleshooted patron's technology related issues
- Maintained an approachable and helpful attitude

Education-----

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science | Certificate, Mathematics | 3.813/4.000 | 2017-2021

Awards and Activities:

- Graduated with Distinguished Honors: ranked within the top 20% of the College of Letters & Science
- Dean's List: Fall 2017, Spr/Fall 2018, Spr/Fall 2019, Spr 2021
- Intramural Soccer: Team Manager and Player (Fall 2017 Spring 2020)
- Intramural Dodgeball: Team Manager and Player (Fall 2017 Spring 2020)
- Intramural Rocket League: Player (Fall 2019 Spring 2021)

Projects-----

Unity Game Prototypes: Series of personal projects designed to learn the basics of Unity. Completed a ~42 hour training tutorial and developed several prototype games along the way. Planning to continue to learn and master Unity and C# through personal game projects. Prototypes can be played at: https://play.unity.com/u/nick-mewhirter

- Technologies Used: Unity, C#, Visual Studio

Badger Textbooks: Team-based senior project. Developed a React web-app designed to be the 'goto' application for UW-Madison students looking to sell their used textbooks to other UW students. Worked as a part of a six student team to complete the application while following a modified waterfall SD lifecycle.

- Technologies Used: VSCode, JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Firebase, Github

Final Defender: The Last Stand: Personal project. Developed a game that is currently available on the Apple App Store. Worked to design and develop an 'arcade-style' game and actively monitor the game's status and provide updates as needed. App Store Page can be found at: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/final-defender-the-last-stand/id1476469975

- Technologies Used: XCode, Swift, Photoshop

Skills-----

Technical: Java, JavaScript, Typescript, CSS, React, Python, Swift, C, C++, C#, SQL, Unity, Agile Methodologies, Object Oriented Programming, Mathematics, Photoshop

Interpersonal: Team Leadership, Communication, Teamwork